all righty Joel let me let me ask you
this to start this one out okay have you
ever been to the Golden
Corral I don't think
so really you've never been to Golden
Corral no I think I've only seen their
TV commercials it's like one of those
like 3:00 a.m. commercials you're like
like dude so recently I had I had been
to the Golden Crown maybe like you know
three or four times in my life and then
we recently started going a little bit
that place rocks man you roll up in
there and there's like a whole Buffet
anything you want you know just classic
American mentality here you know and
that Joel is kind of like what we got
today on the Pod CU we have aish board a
buffet of different research and news to
talk about today that was the wildest
transition you've done
ever not digging my intro not digging it
oh no that was great that was great that
was crazy though I had no idea where
that was going hey man the Golden Corral
we started Golden Corral number one from
the from from the podcast today all
right man dude uh we got we got a ton of
I mean we we probably have 12 uh
different things we we got on the list
today so I don't know if we'll get
through all this um but tell you what
let's not go in the order we have in the
doc let's talk about this uh this port
swiger research um release first because
whenever Port swiger research comes out
with something new
gosh darn it it's going to be a banger
bro this was actually the best timing
ever because I was testing something and
specifically I
needed a URL validation bypass yep and I
was like hey this
is extremely topical and I just plugged
it so for those who don't know uh before
I get ahead of myself ports wiger came
out with a new cheat sheet so they have
the all these cheat sheets where
basically like you know it I think
calling it a cheat sheet is a bit of uh
uh not really doing it justice because
it it's more like an interactive payload
generator I guess um where basically you
know they have these for for various
other scenarios I think the xss one ISS
one is is phenomenal I think that's
probably the biggest one that I'm aware
of other than this one uh I'm sure
there's other ones but the xss one is
great you basically just say like I'm on
this browser and I'm in this element
type mhm give me every payload and it'll
say okay you can do on key down on key
up on load on Hover on whatever right um
so that's really awesome they also made
one now for URL validation so
essentially you can put in the Target
domain that it you know passes
validation you can put in the attacker
domain that you're trying to get to and
then you can set different things like
URL encoding Unicode escapes um whether
or not to use special characters um
there's there's IPv6 ipv4 or like all
these different things and it just spits
out a list and you just copy it to your
clipboard and you can paste that in
kaido you can paste that in wherever
burp I guess I should say yeah I guess
we should say sorry for Twingle team
it's your product we should lead with
burp this time faced it into burp um
yeah no but I I um yeah but as far as I
know yeah can you can you paste into
burp or do you have to I think you can
I'm pretty sure you you can paste from
clipboard um but anyways yeah so so
basically just you get a list of
possible options and you can just paste
this into your proxy of choice and um
test all of the different bypass option
really really awesome it's really good
it's nice because it allows you to
specify an allow domain name and an
attacker domain name as well so you
don't have to like do these like you
know said commands to like pop in your
domain and then sometimes they're like
encoded a little weird so it doesn't do
it like it automatically does all of it
um which is super awesome and then
there's various advanced settings as
well including like various ipv4 to IPv6
Transformations um Cloud metadata points
just tons of stuff yeah yeah yeah so
very very cool very awesome tool um it
it also has uh built into this it's not
just for absolute URLs right so like
maybe it's for an open redirect or
something like that but it's also for
host headers so maybe you're trying to
get access to an internal tool you're
trying to do some vhost bypass they have
host header generation for the same
typee of stuff so basically you put in
the allow domain the target domain that
you trying to hit and it'll generate you
a list of host header options it also
has cores options um so very very
awesome tool they made a little blog
post about it as well if you're curious
about sort of the background behind it
but um I'm sure if you haven't seen it
on Twitter already you can find the link
down uh down below but yeah very very
helpful tool especially if you're trying
to bypass some URL validation parsing
open redirects RFS you name it this is
so so pretty too dude because you hover
over each one of the URLs right just
hover over those and you'll see a uh
like a name or a bypass like
categorization for this specific why
this works that might be new I I don't
think that was there when I first tried
this but this is awesome sfari allows
left parenthesis as subdomain
HTP allowed. sub. left parentheses. ATT
hackers slash that yeah these are
awesome this is it's like it's like the
marriage of of Shazer and and
like I don't thinks
I Shazer and Che the fuzz like the
fuzzing side of like chazzer where it's
like you know browser specific stuff and
all these weird quirks and whatever
combined with just like I have this
thing and this thing get me there and
yeah yeah well I I was looking at it
though and it's it's you know obviously
released by ports veger research but
it's created by uh d4d uh and it's l
linked down at the bottom of the um of
the cheat sheet um but so it's not even
Gareth and and there is like shout outs
to Gareth like it says in the the the
the big thanks to section the first one
on the list is there's a lot of names
down here I think next time I make a
tool I'm just going to shout out all the
people that I like and hope that they're
like oh thanks oh yeah I don't big
thanks to uh fron Rosen Orange um any
body who's ever inspired me no this is
great though really um really high
quality quality thing here um definitely
going to be using that and man it saves
us so much time too because there's so
much like encoding that you have to do
to really like thoroughly bypass things
and you just need that one anomaly you
know you just need that one anomaly to
start seeing some some weird stuff there
um yep absolutely absolutely all right
um let's see so okay I said keep the
tool you you want to keep the Tool uh
chain rolling well just we can do that
you want to go down to uh the this one
right here yeah all right all right yeah
let's talk about this okay so this is
really interesting because oh jeez I
mean this had to have been
before covid even I I was working with
smeagles on some like random tool and I
think there was a tool called like
fast. JS or something or like fast. sh I
think is what it was called it was like
really old tool and basically it was
just like designed to do like DNS
lookups and bulk and like detect good
DNS servers and whatever I was like oh
this is like really slow let's let's
make it faster and so I wrote this tool
called fast. py and I think I actually
released it um on my
GitHub fast. let's see no fresh. pie
fresh. pie that's what it is yeah fresh.
P yeah so it was a remix of fresh. yeah
fresh not not fast so fresh fresh. sh
basically just
fetches a bunch of DNS resolvers tests
them tries to find a list of good
resolvers so that you can do big Mass
DNS lookups yeah I was like oh this is
slow so I wrote fresh. pie which did it
way faster and then I also have a
private version of It fresh. Go um and
and that creative naming Joel I love
that you know I try to be original
uh uh yeah so I I completely forgot
about that project and then I don't know
like a month ago Smigel tweets out that
the company that uh he founded
co-founder of hadrien uh has this new
tool called Sanic DNS that does I mean
it definitely blows my tool like way out
of the water this is also this does full
resolutions as well this is like a it's
not just like DNS alternative exactly
it's not just like clean resolver
finding it's very
like in I mean like okay 5 million
lookups per set
second that's insane man I I feel like
the resolvers I feel like at 5 million
like resolves per second you're just
going to like the resolvers are going to
be like okay that guy is actually
becoming a problem now like it's one of
those things where like so I I think uh
the only time I really hit this Crux was
when I got 10 gig service at my house in
californ god dude and here we go again
with the 10 gig service thing here's the
thing when you get an Internet that fast
you realize oh yeah most things actually
are
designed to like work with networks this
fast um and I think you'll probably get
to find a very similar thing with Sanic
D which is that like most DNS resolvers
and infrastructure is not designed to do
5 million requests per second so uh
that's going to that's definitely going
to be something you're going to have to
probably work around a little bit yeah
um but you know if you really want to
see those types of speeds that being
said even if it works at like a fraction
of that like 1 million DNS
second totally crazy and I love how the
first step if you go to the the get up
repo for this the first step of getting
started is you're going to need more
memory so go ahead and and like allocate
yourself another extra gigabyte of
memory with like uh DP DK huge Pages um
so that's that's pretty that's pretty
hilarious also I love can I just say I
love the artwork for this like they just
got Sonic like got to go fast and then
the Sonic uh the Sanic meme in there so
is that is that Meme actually Sanic like
is that yeah that's the Sanic meme okay
see I I I was disc connected from now I
thought they were just being silly dad
and now he's like full Boomer yeah you
know hey man completely disconnected
from internet culture from internet
memes great great thanks for that um but
yeah dude this is um I think this is you
know every couple years we see a core
tool that I think is used by uh a lot of
a lot of um
people get uh unseated or whatever right
somebody somebody takes the crown and I
think this one might take it from masts
um I've been I've used mdns for the past
a long time um and it looks like this
might be the move now and I actually I
actually passed this off to Donut as
well because um you know Donut's kind of
like my go-to guy when I'm talking about
High Performance Tools I'm like because
he knows what's up with that right he's
he wrote a really high performance Port
scanner and stuff like that and he just
sort of skimmed the code and took a look
at it and he said that it seems like
they're doing all these things right
they're using something that I had never
even heard of called XDP sockets which
apparently stands for Express data path
sockets um which I guess is just Express
sockets I don't know like sockets but
faster you yeah I think it's like
basically like kernel level sockets is
sort of the idea I mean like there's a
certain point right where you start to
get Capp by userland stuff and you need
you need things to be like lower level
uh uh or higher I guess lower level
whatever you want lower level to to to
be you know optimally fast so like one
of the things that's in the uh in the
read me that talks that it talks about
is like it has this i40e driver support
so it can hook directly it can bind
directly onto the Nick like oh really
and it works with like 10 gig and up
right so it's like 10 25 and 40 gig uh
cards oh my like inck cards and then it
can do you know they said on a 40 gig
line they were able to do seven and a
half million requests per second oh my
gosh that's like you know with with
their own resolver but even still like
that's just like redonkulous so very
very cool I I feel like this is one of
those tools that you develop out of
necessity which uh is pretty awesome so
it just kind of shows you like what sort
of like the end game uh version of like
DNS lookups and stuff looks like when
you're like really trying to do it at
scale and do efficiently I wonder I
wonder what not is doing with um with
DNS lookups like whether they're they're
wrapping Mass DNS or whether they've got
a say I've had some really in-depth
conversations with the folks over there
about how they do stuff uh I don't think
I'm going to say anything specific but
um they definitely do some really cool
stuff and um you know similar to this
you have to push sort of the boundaries
of how you're like you have to really
rethink how you do stuff in order to
break through you know these sort of
limit caps yeah yeah I agree very cool
so new normally we we don't really cover
you know big Recon stuff super much on
here but um I think a a tool unseating
Mass DNS as the go-to DNS resolver is
probably a good one to mention so um
that's why I bring that up okay so let
me go back to what I was saying before
okay um which was on the podcast a
couple weeks ago probably now um I
talked about the um the writeups from
Orange from this uh this past Defcon
black hat and um I mentioned that I
hadn't you know when I went to go
reproduce it I was like ah ah [__] my
Apache is actually patched and I I
didn't actually even like intentionally
patch it it was it was just patched
already um and so I was like dang I
don't really feel like spinning up this
whole thing or whatever and and so I I
just didn't didn't continue with the
with the uh reproducing of it um but uh
then I saw on Twitter that uh
harc uh released a GitHub recall uh
GitHub recall GitHub Repo Man it's it's
the morning man I gotta I got to take my
my coffee um a GitHub repo called orange
confusion attacks and essentially he
dockerized all of these um attacks that
orange released in that in that
presentation which is super duper
helpful so you can play with them and
like fine-tune your tools if you're
trying to get some detection going for
it um so we'll drop that link down in
the description but the i i dude I just
so appreciate when people do this sort
of thing where they minimize that
friction piece to like playing around
with something new and I would love to
see more people integrate that into
their research flow um and say like hey
you know I'm releasing some new research
on
XYZ here is a Docker container that you
can use to reproduce this like boom like
no problem you know yeah that's exactly
what I was going to say I think like
creating a Docker container I mean as
you're doing research it's probably not
your first thought because I C myself
doing this all the time where I start to
over complicate things and if I were to
think about like oh I want to do
research on this web server like let me
dockerize the whole process like before
I even like that's basically definition
over complicating things yeah so I would
probably have stopped myself there that
being
said if you're going to release it make
it easy you know for people to do that
sort of research and just like go that
extra mile and it'll make it so much
better so that you know I love harc I
love orange but yeah the fact that you
know one of them had to do the the extra
mile for the other is you know yeah it's
great you know and so I think I think
one if you want to be a member of the
community that that like does something
like this and that's like your thing I
think that would be super cool I think
you would get really popular um if you
just started tweeting out like pretty
good at generating Docker files exactly
here's here's the research um here's the
docker file so you can reproduce it I
mean super helpful um and then you know
to any of you guys out there that are
actually producing um like your own
security research that that would also I
think is would be would be massive and I
dude I also feel like I feel like Docker
is just kind of like a high value skill
for security researchers to just
understand uh you know even if you're
not doing Docker container security or
anything like that but like I think if
you just understand how it works and um
and are able to spin up Docker
containers easily and create Docker
containers pretty easily um I think that
that is a very high value skill it it
will save you a lot of time and effort
yeah for sure I mean it's one of those
Technologies where it's like it's like
for me like I would view it almost as
like Linux right or like knowing how to
use a shell where it's like it's it's
sort of one of those fundamental
technologies that at minimum you should
you should be like familiar with and
understand like The Core Concepts of
even if you don't like understand it at
a super low level like just knowing like
oh okay there's containers and these
containers are like templated and you
can have like commands and this Docker
file like sets up like a container in
like a specific way that's like
reproducible like just like knowing like
the basics of what Docker is how to use
it have some have some experience with
it like if you don't have that take a
day like on the this it's worth it I
mean it really is like you know take a
day out of your weekend just like sit
down for a couple hours like install
Docker create some basic containers FID
around with it like read through through
some docks it it'll be worth your while
and I feel like I like I'm sitting here
preaching this right and I've done this
multiple times but I also not really to
the level where I'm like yeah you know I
I I'm a Docker guy you know I can use
Docker you know like but that's fine
right like you you've hit the minimum
like you know like it's one of those
things where I'm not scared of it but
also I'm not like Ah that's easy you
know and I feel like but I also think
like you don't need to necessarily know
like you know it's not it's not like so
mandatory that you should like everybody
should know everything about Docker like
if you're doing a project that involves
Docker like a great example you want to
reverse engineer some software and
there's a docker container for it
mhm most people aren't going to know how
to do that like how to do what like pull
files out of a Docker container I only
know how to do it cuz I wanted to do
that specifically and I looked up how to
do it and if I wanted to do it again I
would have to look it up again um so
like it's just one of those things that
like you know you get familiar with it
out of necessity and uh you know what
you know learn it as you need it right
yeah yeah I feel that man yeah I I think
I think for me I I it's not something
that I I use super duper often because I
I'm not doing a lot of this like uh uh
patch reverse engineering or like even
really going after enterprise software
that often but um whenever I sit down
and I actually am like oh let me just
like build a Docker container for this
or you know how spin up this Docker
container it's like that I'm like a that
was much easier than I expected it to be
and maybe I shouldn't let these these um
you know inhibitions hold me back in a
lot of in a lot of scenarios yeah yeah
um all right so dude next one um
actually I do have I do have a
transition for this one you ready for
this so actually this is super way out
there because I was GNA say you you know
what a Docker container that I have
built is which is the WordPress testing
environment Docker container um and and
also related to
Wordpress cut cut no no no Joe we don't
do cuts on this
man we don't do cuts all right um no so
I I did want to shout this this right up
out though because it's it's super good
so um the write up of course the that
I'm talking about is the uh WordPress
give WP uh pop chain to rce write up
done by um Mr Tux racer and when Mr Tux
racer drops anything specifically
WordPress stuff like he's just quite
good with WordPress stuff um his tweet
have a minimum bar of being like rce or
Worse yeah yeah like like rce or Global
Universal
rce um yeah so I I think this was a
really good write up I think he did he
does a good job of I mean clearly he
went in there and like you know
reproduced it thoroughly himself and I
love the little details that he added in
here so for example let me let me read
you this um he's talking about the the
situation or the specific um location
where uh the deserialization is
happening um in this chain and he says
uh PHP object injection exploits usually
reference class names using their name
spaces which might contain slashes strip
slashes deep tries to get rid of these
by calling strip slashes on every value
however this can be easily bypassed by
using four backs slashes um in the
namespace names and I just like this
this sort of detail might be something
that a lot of write up people would just
sort of solve themselves and then skip
over and not include you know in the
actual write up itself but I I find
stuff like this extremely useful and
also kind of counterintuitive like why
does strip slashes allow a backslash in
the actual final result like that
shouldn't be how that works and so I
literally sat down and I was like all
right I got to play with this so I I I
spun up a little PHP thing and I was
playing with it and essentially I think
the reason why it works is
because um it will it will escape you
know if you have four backslashes right
it will convert
the two backslashes it'll remove one of
the backlashes right because one of them
is an escaped character and one of them
is a is a backslash it'll remove that so
it's just a backslash and then it'll do
the same one for the next one and now
you've got two backslashes right next to
each other which is an escaped backslash
again so it produces a a backslash um
and it's just not something that I would
have really like intuitively tried to in
this situation so it's just great to be
aware of the fact that those that strip
slashes can be bypassed in PHP yeah so
dude this is one of those like mental
gadgets right it's it's like the little
nugget that you get from reading this
like you read through this cool research
does it apply how many times you going
to see give WP probably not that often
how many times you going to see an
outdated give WP almost never however
that's not really the important part
right the important part is how does
this work like understanding that and
then separately the little nuggets like
the strip slashes and how that works
because the next time you see something
you know maybe you know it's PHP maybe
you don't know it's PHP maybe you do
some fingerprinting and find out its
PHP now you have something to add in
your payload specifically targeted
towards PHP because maybe they're using
strip slashes and you can exploit in
this way so it's just you know those
little those little mental gadgets you
know you don't even have to remember it
specifically you just you're like oh man
what was that
uher it'll it notice it right you see
strip slashes and you start staring at
it and you're like why am I staring at
at strip slashes like why do I feel like
there's something weird about that and
then you'll you'll look it up start
searching like strip slashes bug Bounty
rce right exctly yeah exactly RC RC will
get you there um yeah no that's great
man um a couple other takeaways that I
had for this one was um the entry point
for this attack and we talked about this
a little bit way back in episode
I don't know whatever number it was
where we we started um we talked about
WordPress security a lot but um one of
the main ways to do WordPress security
um in a lot of the the API flows is to
have these nonces in place and sometimes
these nonces will only be uh accessible
from um Pages where uh admins can access
or something like that right but
technically the endpoint where you
utilize the nons doesn't actually
require that privilege right you anybody
can hit that endpoint but if you don't
have the NS it's going to freak out
right as I was reading through this I
was like oh man the Stars just keep uh
another one just aligns no it's
beautiful and and but I think that's a
really good call out for anybody who is
looking at word WordPress stuff is like
if you have the um you know where
they're doing the ad action and it's
wpor Ajax right that can be triggered by
you know even a subscriber level user
right and and if there's not a an actual
permission check on that there's just a
non verification check then it you may
be able to leak that nons and actually
call that function still um and you know
even more so if it's like WPA Jack's no
priv and you can just hit it from an
unauthenticated perspective or like
admin in it or something like that so um
I I and I've I've got some we've got
some automation actually set up in the
um in the critical thinkers channel uh
for the data streams section where um we
automatically scan every um new new
commit done to uh WordPress plugins
above 50,000 uh installs and we use a um
tree to go through as tree yeah tree
tree AB tree yeah AB syrax tree to go
through and like look for these
verification nonces and um lack of uh
ways for checking various CR or um roles
within the WordPress apis um so we catch
a lot of those bugs when those come
through I think that that script
probably pops out a couple CVS a month
at least um uh that that just get handed
off to the critical thinkers community
and and uh they make a couple bucks on
it here and there but I think this sort
of situation where you have a nons and
the nons is in place but the non is
actually leak is a is a more complicated
situation that um would be a little bit
more if you're doing intentional
research on a plugin yeah yeah
absolutely and on top of that yeah
yesterday I got an email I'll give a
little free shout out here okay from the
word fence folks all right um who are
now running a couple different um bug
Bing promotions on their thing they've
in they've added xss vulnerabilities on
anything over a thousand plus installs
into scope they have increased bounties
they have a new install tier for plugins
with over 5 million active installs um
with bounties up to 30k so wow I
mean we have alerts for plugins
there's some new research on plugins
there's some higher bounties for plugins
so maybe uh maybe this weekend if you
want to go check out uh some of the
WordPress plugins and go get some 30k
bounties serious Bounty yeah that's
that's legit legit so very very cool
stuff um and uh you know I don't think
WordPress is going anywhere anytime soon
so it's used everywhere man so it is
really a high value thing to know the
ins and outs of so the weird thing is
like it'll be used on like sites that
you would never expect to be WordPress
like you'll just run Recon and and like
my nuclei will say hey by the way this
is running WordPress I'm like heck this
is running WordPress and then I run a WP
scan and you know oh it's got like all
these different plugin so definitely uh
definitely not going anywhere yeah I'm
GNA look up the episode really quick um
yeah popping word press plugins
methodology brain dump uh episode 55 is
the one where we we joined by that uh
word fence researcher and we kind of
talk about what the approach is to hack
WordPress bugs or uh find find WordPress
vulnerabilities because you know at the
end of the day it's PHP right so of
course you know if somebody's just
putting a PHP file out there and they're
just like you know echoing dollar
signore get whatever then you're going
to you're going to get xss but um
there's also a lot of custom PHP uh
WordPress synergies that happen what the
only thing I'll say is okay the only
times I've ever used PHP ever is in the
most hacky of
situations it like I never write a PHP
POC when I'm like H I just I just need
something normal it's like when I need
some really weird like I need to add a
header in the response in real time like
some like that's a you problem I'm
running eval and like the head like dude
actually have you seen the whole and we
won't we won't Rabbit Trail down this
for too long but have you seen the like
movement lately surrounding like
reverting to PHP and jQuery and just
shipping really fast for like dude let's
go I'm so here for it the levels IO like
I know you said we weren't going to
Rabbit Hole in this but I la a week or
two ago I was just like just for fun I
went down the the cursor Rabbit Hole uh
gosh with like AI code writing and
projects and stuff and uh I literally
got to the point where I was like okay I
don't want any react I want basic HTML I
want this look like 90s website like
straight HTML JavaScript and it it
actually worked way better dude it it's
it's it's a real thing man I think uh I
think there's something to be said about
just using the minimum required you know
technology to do it okay all right Joel
I'm I'm raining us back in okay last
last comment that I want to I want to
have on this one is if you're not
familiar with pop chains I think that's
a pretty cool V class to at least
understand if you if you like to geek
out over stuff um and it's it's a
deserialization you know uh technique uh
but man those things are fun to research
and when when we were going down the uh
the WordPress Rabbit Hole back earlier
this year um it's just I had so much fun
hunting for popchain gadgets uh to allow
allow to Pivot from class to class and
actually get arbitrary code execution um
and this example here in the um in the
uh blog post by by Mr Tux racer is is
pretty awesome I think he he pulled this
graphic from the yeah he did he pulled
it from the word fence team's blog
um but I I appreciate when they break
down all that and allow us to see the
beauty of what a pop chain looks like in
its full Glory cuz like this is what
five steps before it even gets to the
code execution so you're you're in deep
deep by the time you actually pop
something yeah very much so I mean it's
one of those scenarios where you're like
is this actually GNA pop and when it
does oh man feel so good feels feels so
good dude all right awesome where you
want to go another tool another tool
it's it's tool Tuesday uh uh
okay it really
is Joel hey man hey thank you for
evening evening the score because I I
did a crappy transition earlier so um
all right dou Tuesday you're done
talking now wait that was the best
transition of all time go go all right
so yes we hack yes we hack has released
a tool called xss tools this been around
for a while dude just FYI they released
it three years
ago um yeah no it's crazy I have
literally never heard of this thing you
linked this uh up until uh five seconds
ago I thought this was brand new brand
new release um I L it to one of my
friends he was like what this is cool so
it this is awesome um so the the best
way I can uh analogize this analogize I
can make an analogy for this is this is
a terrible analogy oh my God anybody I'm
sorry this is maybe the worst way I can
make it LG anybody who's used pone tools
before uh for like
native Native exploitation binary
exploitation
um yeah so pone tools is like this
python library that you can import and
you just do like from pone import Star
and then you just have all these
functions that are like awesome like
help for functions you can like decode
stuff this actually prad break points
whatever so this like is kind of like
that but for xss so it's like this
Library you just import this JS file and
then it gives you all these functions
that you can call so you you know you
just do like payload do new then you do
add X filtrat and you give it a function
to exfiltrate and you do eval and then
it like runs some code and you
exfiltrate and it exfiltrate it to your
exfil trator and fetch Dom and it like
gets a page from the right so it does
like all these like it it's just a lot
of helper functions that like if you
were to write an xss uh payload like you
you're you have an xss you want to
exploit it and like build out a PC
Building out the PC is big pit so big
jeez it is a big pain dude much like
your throat is experiencing right
now but um but yeah it's really awesome
the the ex filtrat piece I think is
really is really cool too right because
listen to this there's listen to these
exfiltrated uh post message exfiltration
get Bas exfiltration uh send based
exfiltration image exfiltration iframe
exfiltration so like the it's it's got a
bunch of scenarios for ways when you
have limited exfiltration methodologies
and you don't have to like go and write
all this custom code for it you just
import the library and boom boom boom so
yeah yeah dude um bit K dropped this on
me when he was doing the um the the
Prototype pollution master class in the
in the critical thinkers Discord and uh
I was like wow how have I not heard of
this because I feel like this would save
a bunch of time but but but also let me
just say
this kind of gets like this I think this
was way
cooler before AI because like now I can
just I literally just go to chat gbt or
whatever and I'm like all right write
this to do this and then it it just does
it and it works so well um um the one
thing I will say though I think there
are probably some areas where you can
improve this a little bit because like
chat gbt is good for like basic stuff um
when it gets like more complicated
little it can maybe it's okay sometimes
um but like when you're talking about ex
filtrates I'm thinking okay let's add
the ports swigger CSS blind exfiltration
technique as an exfiltrate and let's
like update this because this is you
know three years out of date now so
there's probably some other exfiltration
methods that have come up since then
that that's the first one that came to
mind and uh then you know in those
really weird scenarios I think this
still has a really good use case where
you want to write a really high quality
POC that just works and you can just
do this and it just works yeah so dude
but also check this out like there's
there's a a payload here within here
that says start key logger like that's
the kind of stuff that I that that it's
nice to have like modulized right
because it's like ah I know it's
possible is in the read me it's awesome
yeah I I I know that it's it's it's
possible for me to like do a key logger
but then I got to like write all the
JavaScript and like you know exfiltrate
it out but this thing will just
automatically do it so um oh oh oh okay
also I'm sorry Joel the the other thing
that I was really excited about which is
kind of ironic because it's clickjacking
but um is the is the clickjacking
functionality here okay so listen listen
up critical critical thinking listeners
here okay um I'm not warranting I'm not
saying that clickjacking is a valid bug
in you were he first most of the
situations at the bottom of your reports
Rino Raider told me that clickjacking is
a valid report please accept Bounty
please no um but there are scenarios I
have had a clickjacking accepted as a
high when you have uh like a click
checking on for example on an oath
approval page where you can just force
the but you know they click one button
and now their account is pwned Right
valid the thing is these things are a
pain in the ass to write because you've
got to like align all the things and
where's the button who knows you know
and it's a whole it's a whole step but
this uh this this library has a
clickjunkie I'm just going to read from
the read me here writing clickjacking
code can be tedious with xcess tools you
only need to supply the position of the
target element on the on the on the
target page and then you're good to go
and I'm just like ah yes this is what I
need this is what I need it's so good I
mean this is this is awesome um I I love
Little Helper tools like this um and
okay bad transition number two are you
ready are you done with this one no no
no I'm not done okay also okay Finish
finish okay let me just say Let me let
me add one more thing about the click
Jacker okay
um not only did they did they build that
into it right but they also G gave us
this little oneliner down at the bottom
that says hey you can find the the
bounding box interactively using this
code so they just give you like a
JavaScript oneliner that you can just
toss into your into your script console
it's these little the little Snippets
man dud it's it's clutch little nuggets
it's so clutched so um yeah I'm sorry
that's all I wanted to say it's just
really helpful for uh uh xssx filtration
and um in clickjacking PC's so okay take
it away go ahead well the impact is is
right here you know it's they give you
the impact in the read me and you know
what else reminds me of impact somebody
in our Discord in the hacking channel oh
my God Joel that
ballant okay this guy this was nuts this
was actually nut this was crazy I'm not
going to lie like normally I'm like uh
skeptical of injection injection HTML
injection whatever okay this is pretty
big brain I will not lie uh this guy
found uh I guess it's just HDML
injection right dude I dude it's
actually not even HTML injection this is
text injection Joel this is text
injection just text injection this is
not even HTML there there is not a bug
here right it's it's like bug question
mark uh so what they did is they
realized hang on a second you ever seen
those ASI art
those those big like the man's dancing
in the chat you know on like twitch chat
and it's all asky art yeah so he was
like hang on a second big brain
moment and then he built a QR
code out of these asy Unicode uh
characters whatever like solid like the
solid white squares and then like the
like shaded Square characters or
whatever I I don't know how to describe
this without a screenshot um but yeah
they basically they built a code yeah
our editors can put this up but there's
a screenshot in our Discord from this
guy in the hacking Channel um and uh
it's just text injection but it's it
builds out a QR code and I don't know
you scan the so Joel I talked to him you
scan the QR code and it takes over your
account right and so it's like this is
amazing dude like this is I will say I
will say I will say he went through a
lot of effort here uh to redact the URL
and and like all of the surrounding
stuff all the surrounding stuff and then
the raw QR code oh the raw QR code's
there okay [__] maybe we can't put it up
on the screen dang it I will say uh you
probably could just open in
Chrome oh my gosh I'm trying it takes me
to a thing hello from I'm going to guess
that's probably the target dud dude
don't say it on air now we got to bleep
it I didn't say I didn't say it I I just
said I'm hello from
blank okay so maybe
we yeah okay so I don't know maybe we'll
put it up on the screen maybe we won't
but what I wanted to bring an exercise
okay Joel Just you take a second because
I think you're crying over there right
now this is such a beautiful exploit I
just wanted to bring this bring this um
to the to listeners because dude isn't
this such a beautiful representation of
hacker mentality right like like text
injection classic na bug right doesn't
matter at all but this guy figures out a
way to use some
technical prowess to use his knowledge
of of Unicode and I think he also had
like some sort of tangental CSS
injection on this page that allowed him
to do some like CSS realigning or
whatever um but to make this QR code and
then he uses his knowledge of the app to
take that when that Q code actually gets
scanned it it it does something you know
bad to their to their account so I
presumably they're using like uh same
sight strict or something like that
which is why it needs to originate from
um well no I I'm not I'm not sure that
should just be a se- surf so maybe it's
just a part of the the attack
methodology but he went the the full the
full way to build out this whole POC and
when you do that man doesn't your heart
just like swell with pride like what it
swells with is I hope triage didn't just
go we're having trouble reproducing this
bug like because like this is one of
those things where I think when it like
if you can get it to the team it's like
a beautiful side of bug Bounty that is
so creative yeah and so like out of the
box thinking that is so cool where it's
like you have like chat GPT couldn't
come up with that [__] in a million
years okay like straight up you could
feed that prop you could click the
regenerate button a thousand times it'll
never be like you should generate a QR
code with asky characters
with your text injection right like that
is it's such a cool like unique um
attack scenario and it's so creative
like I If I had received that I'd been
like all right at minimum low Bounty
just for creativity well dude it like I
think it also just kind of pays for
itself a little bit too you know not not
to say that that you don't need to pay
for these super crazy bugs because I
think the company should but like when
you get to the end of that that I just
finished a PC last night for a bug that
I am super proud of that's like uh like
you know it's it's funny I call it like
a Matan bear bug now after that episode
cuz it's like and then I do this and I
grab this cookie and then overflow the
cookie J like this and that and the
other thing and you it comes together
and it's so smooth and clean and you
just it feels so good you know um and
then the next morning triage goes hey do
you own this
domain yeah exactly lovely yeah it's ups
and downs the bug Bounty man that's
never happened to me before
just thank you for that Joel um but yeah
I think uh shout out to baland here from
the from the Discord this is a very cool
uh strategy of tech text injection and
unicode characters to build out a QR
code um very cool very cool indeed all
right let's let's see what else we got
on the list for today dude
um okay Le let's jump back up to this uh
uh browser tracking protection thing
okay okay I'm going to let you take this
one I I got dense AF yes it was it was
very dense I didn't even know this was a
thing by the way and it took me a very
like more Google searches than it should
have to even find out what this ITP
thing is I was like what is ITP and
every was like ITP is a mechanism for I
was like no no no what is it what what
does ITB stand for yeah exactly and and
and so essentially what this article is
and we'll link down below it's um it's
bypassing browser tracking prevent or
protection for Cores uh misconfiguration
abuse by um the PT security team um and
essentially what this blog post does is
it details um safaris and firefox's
answer of sorts to Chrome's same site
lacks okay so what they've done in
Firefox and uh Safari is they've
implemented these uh tracking
protections that happened by by default
um which prevent cookies from being sent
to third party domains so that you're
not getting tracked by like oh you came
to this website and there was like a
pixel for whatever and it said a cookie
and now we know who you are forever
right um uh and and and these have been
kind of foiling um exploits for a little
while like I've been I've heard some
murmur in the critical thinking um
Discord and and in the community a
little bit of like man this exploit
works fine here but it doesn't work over
here like why is that happening um and
it's because Firefox and and Safari have
implemented you so um the tldr of the
situation is that uh you you won't be
able to send not top level um request so
like a fetch request or whatever with
with credentials with it in Safari or
Firefox if you don't first do a window.
open to the the vulnerable page okay and
so what this means is that if you do see
uh vulnerable cores configurations
nowadays typically I've been kind of not
paying attention to those very much
because uh same site kind of screw with
that if it's cookie based authentication
which it has to be for for that um but
this is still very possible in in
Firefox and in Safari because um you
just need to harvest one click to open
up a window and when you do that uh at
least in Firefox is is the case um
there's a relationship between those two
domains stored for 30 days so let's say
I do it from you know my p. rat.com to
google.com I do a window. openen right
so so now pc. rat.com can send
credential requests to google.com for 30
days okay and um and so all you got to
do is do that window. open and then
you're good to go uh I think Safari you
have to wait like two seconds or
something like that because of something
janky um yeah it's kind of weird you got
to use like a set timeout or whatever
before you can send the request but um
but the this this attack still
absolutely works and the majority of
this blog post was just explaining the
setup and explaining what this thing is
and the way that they went about you
know building a test environment for it
which is cool and helpful if you want to
play around with it a little bit more
but I was a little bit over underwhelmed
when I got to the end and I was like oh
it's just like window. open okay cool
you know like I'll do that crazy that's
really that's really really interesting
it kind of reminds me so uh I don't know
I don't think I added I added this and
then I removed it because I I knew you
wouldn't have time to read it but I
don't know if you if you saw there was
this CTF WR up oh my gosh dude from IDK
CTF
2024 um and this is this the I frame
thing yeah yeah dude I read it dude my
menty sent it to me as soon as like
three days ago yeah and and I I woke up
and I like looked at looked at the
message I was like oh what's this I
clicked on it and it was like 6:00 a.m.
in the morning I was reading it groggy
and I'm like oh my gosh this is insane I
can't even process any of this it's
insane but like you know there's a lot
of this like sort of similar Behavior
where like if you like load a page first
then it like allow it sets like
different CSP Behavior or like uh sorry
not CSP um yeah cross orig CSP or
sandboxing behavior depending it inherit
the CSP and then it like yeah I also
need to reread because it was so D dude
I read through it I was like what the
heck like there was like new uh
attributes that I didn't even know like
iframe sandbox and iframe um Source do
yeah now we're going to have to find
that link and put it in the descrip I
put I put it at the bottom uh but yeah
we'll maybe we'll save that for next
week yeah maybe we will because I
actually would like to go back and and
reread that and get a more concrete grip
on it because that iframe stuff and the
attribute inheritance and like all of
that is really um is really tricky um
but yeah I I just want to swing back
around to this uh this browser tracking
protection thing for a second because I
feel like this is one of those issues
that kind of like slid under the radar
and has been kind of foiling PC's uh uh
you know and you're like why is this
working I know that this should work um
this is this is very well could be the
reason if you're in Firefox or Safari so
um just do a window. open to your target
page anytime within the past 30 days
from that origin and you're you're good
to go um all right oh here's the other
dude I had another one one more
interesting takeaway from this um this
setting is not a I was kind of curious
about how this setting gets stored right
let me let me take a sip of something
real quick because I I my throat is
hecking
up okay
um this is not stored I was kind of
wondering how this was stored right and
so I was like I wonder if this could
actually tell us whether we have in been
on a specific website or not within the
past um however many days by detecting
whether we could send a cross origin
request to to that website right um and
and turns out you can and even if you go
and you clear your browser history if
you go to that that website and you send
a a request and it sends cookies that
setting is still there okay hear me out
hear me out yeah there's a canary there
I don't know if you realized it but in
the same way that you can like CSS
exfiltrate with like you know like the
sort of like TR like if it goes through
then that's an indicator so you could
Brute Force like you know cross leak of
sorts right right right right like you
know if the request goes through then
you know that path exists so you brute
force paths until you hit one that
exists
and yeah I mean you you but here's the
thing you have to inal you have to
control JavaScript execution on the
website in of that or oh the target oh
yeah so if they clicked on the link then
you should already be able to know that
um that's a little yeah it's it's more
it's more interesting from like a just
general overall security perspective
where it's like okay well I cleared my
browser history but also this uh you
know if I go to you know whatever
website and say fetch has has the user
clicked on a link from this website and
gone to another website and yes that
setting is still stored um so I I just
thought that was an interesting little
tidbit uh I don't think it's a
actionable vulnerability or anything but
um there definitely is some interesting
um Nuance to it because you you can if
you do get an xss you could even trigger
this attack from the client side right
yeah um and if this if it does go
through then you have a a a true or
false on whether the user has logged
into a specific you know or clicked on a
link from this website to a different
website um in in the past 30 days which
is gives you a decent amount of of time
range on it
um so yeah I don't know man a little bit
little bit weird a little bit Fringe but
I figured uh I figured I'd mention it
just because uh generally security
related okay um
yeah let me see yeah this next one all
right I I'll take the Dom clobbering one
as well if you don't mind because I have
been playing around with this lately I
saw this and I was like uh again it's to
Tuesday Man full Tuesday yeah well so
essentially how this conversation
started is I think somebody in the
critical thinkers tier was asking about
Dum clobbering I think it was like xss
doctor or something and then Jay hadex
hopped up in there and dropped this
research on us and uh and we're like
whoa what is what is this and uh there's
some really great research I mean I
think this has been around uh this was
2023 so it's actually pretty recent
research um from somebody named
soale
Kari sorry about that I did my best um
but it's it's it's everything um
everything you wanted to know about D
clobbering but we're afraid to ask and I
think this is a really cool um
presentation for anybody who wants to
like understand Dom clobber at a basic
level and understand how to start
exploiting it um and there's lots of
great information in there but the real
gem that came out of that was this Dom
clob doxyz website that documents a
bunch of like Dom clobbering um
functionality that you can use to
essentially clobber certain variables um
in inside of a Dom when you only have
like HTML injection versus uh xss right
um and within that there is this payload
generator once again the weak of the
payload generator um where you can so
many bookmarks to add man yeah where you
can say like okay the variable I want to
CL clobber is like um response. status
code right and then you just CLI click
generate and it will generate like five
different ways for you to clobber that
variable using an a tag using a form uh
using like a text area inside of a form
and all of these things um and I just
think once again that makes our life
much simp because we know that that
that's possible but now we got to go and
research oh where's you know what
elements should I use is it ID or is it
name you know that's one of the things
that that is kind of tricky about Dom
clobbering so this payload generator
makes it much easier yeah dude you know
I I love I think the way I love to think
about this is like um like a contractor
who has like those like a really
expensive tool right like like a really
like it was an investment but like it
does something very specific very well
and you're like why do you have that
that and it's like because if I didn't
have that I would have to know how to do
it the other way or manually or the old
school way and instead I have invested
in this tool to do it better yeah and
that is exactly what this type of stuff
is like could you go through and like
you know maybe there's something to be
said about like the learning process of
like maybe you do that once like the
first time you do a Dom claing just to
understand like how it works and get all
the background or whatever but then like
use the tool like make your life easier
and like do it more efficiently because
that's why exists like having tools and
using them effectively is like so so
important yeah especially for career
Hunters right like if you're going to be
in um you know security for the rest of
your life like I plan to be like it it
makes sense to invest in these tools and
and build them out um and know about
them and document them for yourself
because sometimes there are people out
there whose thing is Dom clobbering and
they're like going to maintain this
website on do cling for you and uh you
just have to know where it is and how to
use it
yeah yeah so that was that was that was
a great takeaway I I definitely have
been I've been thinking about that a lot
um okay so we got a couple more things
to go through here but I kind of want to
take a pause real quick and just reflect
on that episode that we did with fron uh
like back in in Vegas okay where he was
talking about the um the ex correlation
IDs and the request IDs and what kind of
logging pipelines those get integrated
into um and here here's why I wanted to
to pause about that because I'm I was
thinking like okay so fron found that
thing that's really cool how can we take
that that concept that he he used and
expand it and apply it to other areas
like what are the things like request ID
that I was totally sleeping on right and
and I I definitely should have been
sussing but I just was like ah it's just
request ID like that never does anything
right um and so I started brainstorming
on it a little bit I'll give you some
time to think Joel because I'm kind of
throwing on you last minute but um one
of the things that popped up in my mind
is is um is Sentry Andor like client
side error logging um that that occurs
um you know via Sentry or via some other
provider right and I know that there are
some exploits out there like there's
like a century ssrf I think hacker one
was vulnerable to at one point um and
that sort of thing but I feel like that
environment in general um unless it's
all going back to One dashboard could
have a similar uh effect to what fron
did with the request ID right where you
you throw some payloads in there and
then that goes through the logging
pipeline like ends up in like some
custom dashboard they've built to like
show all of their JS errors or whatever
and then pops and you get access to a
bunch of like logged session tokens or
something like that from the client side
um so yeah that that that's one of the
things I was thinking of do you have
anything in your brain that kind of like
you definitely looked at and thought Ah
that's sketchy but I see it everywhere
no one's exploiting it so I'm just going
to move along yeah I mean there are
definitely things where I sort of draw
the line so like I think I used to be a
lot more like permissive I think in
terms of like things I would consider as
like oh maybe there's a bug here and
like I think where I really have lately
drawn the line is like anything to do
with um well yeah I mean most things to
do with like new account creation new
setup like initial setup account setup
like that kind of stuff like maybe I'll
put some payloads in there yeah but I'm
not super concerned about like recording
the traffic of like a new account setup
because maybe there is a bug in there
like maybe there's some form of an ATO
or something but like most of the time
like this is a one-time scenario that
like happens where like you have very
limited amount of configuration it like
probably won't ever pop up more than
once so if it's something specific that
like a user needs to like hit a certain
URL during the setup phase or something
like that's a very hard attack scenario
to propose to the program it is um that
being said like I'm still going to
record it I'm still going to look like
you know but well I think I think you
can get caught up on that sometimes too
like I I've often spent many times or a
lot of time before the many times man I
don't know what is wrong with me today
man um you know I've spent a lot of time
um pre pre off just kind of playing with
that flow and like trying to get it to
to do something funky or whatever and
I'm like man
99.9% of the functionality of this
application is on the other side of this
process like maybe I should just you
know but I also thought you were going
to go in a different Direction with that
because I've seen a lot of people um pop
crazy stuff on signup flows or like um
one I think under discussed type of bug
is uh signup hijacking if there is some
way for you to predict what kind of
unique identifier the user will get
before they actually have an account and
then and then BR force that to to take
over active signups then I think that
that is a really high value attack
because then you can you can um you know
sometimes you can get access to Pi
that's cached in the signup flow or um
maybe even affect that user's password
whatever um or maybe even just
automatically get logged into their
account if you just play like yeah I
accept the terms and conditions and
that's like the last step and then it
says okay welcome to the website or
whatever right um so yeah I think I
think there's I think this is kind of
like what we talk about when we say
everybody's got their own set of eyes
for for testing right you know fron
looks at their reest ID and says hm I
think that could be weird and you know
there's people that look at the signup
flow and be like that seems a little odd
and then the rest of us sort of skip
over it and that's why it's important to
have a variety of hackers hacking on
your on your on your program um rather
than just like one pent Test Company you
use every year year of a year yep yep
for sure yeah um the did you have any
other anything else you wanted to add to
that um things that are like EXC
correlation ID that you think might be
sketchy but you haven't taken the time
to dive into no but I think like just
generally speaking like it's a very
healthy mindset to like not get
so
like systematic about it all yeah like
repetitive like autopilot right like you
don't want to just be like oh I've seen
that header a million times like taking
a step back and thinking what is that
header like have I ever thoroughly
looked into that and and seeing like
what like why did they send that head
like there's some reason it's not just
there for no reason like some technology
is sending it or some some you know
tracing behind the scenes or like you
know it's there for some reason like
they don't you don't put something in an
application for no reason yeah yeah and
and I think um this is another reason
that I really advocate for spending a
lot of time on an application you know
spending more time than you
are you know comfortable spending
because you get to the point when you're
out of ideas and then you sit there and
you're forced to be creative you're
forced to you're forced to think all
right well what if there was a you know
rce in the request ID you know header
right or like that sort of thing and you
try those things out and you grow as a
hacker um yeah so spend time spend time
go deep guys AB the last thing that I
wanted to mention on that was um I think
those endpoints that return a one pixel
GIF I think are mostly just kind of used
for logging or like um yeah the tracking
pixel yeah tracking pixels and stuff
like that um those don't necessarily
yeah I've never seen anything weird with
those but I do wonder where all that
data ends up and and what kind of ons
there could be there so just a couple
couple thoughts that I had surrounding
all that yeah absolutely
absolutely uh okay last thing second
last thing you posted this link and I
was very confused because it does
nothing for me so maybe you can yeah the
the the one to my website yes okay well
hold up did you oh shoot did I oh wait
now it oh now it even does even less of
something actually it wasn't doing that
before well no no no no no it it works
yeah click click click at the beginning
of the link don't click on the the
middle part so um this is just a here
I'll send it to you in Discord um this
is just a a little uh Quirk of of HTML
that I found out the other day that you
know I want to say I mentioned it on the
Pod but maybe I didn't so I just wanted
to go ahead and mention it um which is
that you can if you have um
a tag injection you can actually trigger
a post request which is something that I
didn't know wait it still doesn't do
anything for you I'm clicking it and I'm
looking at my network Tab and there's
nothing
what no no no it works dude you're
you're tripping I'm on the latest Chrome
you're tripping dude it it works um so
so essentially let me let me just tell
the people about this and we'll
troubleshoot your janky Chrome instance
afterwards um uh so essentially if you
have an a an a tag which I feel like is
one of the more common places where you
can get an injection because a tags are
allowed in markdown um and sometimes you
want to try to trigger a post with that
because um you you want to trigger like
a c surf on the website and it's like uh
maybe it's origin based or uh checks for
Cerf or something like that um and if
you are able to smuggle in the Ping
attribute um then when you click that
the the link it will execute the link
but also we'll send a post request to
wherever you set set the Ping attribute
to um and in the post request Joel I
don't know why you can't see it dude I I
don't know why but it contains some
interesting things it contains a header
ping from and ping to that contains the
Full location hre of the page that
you're on so I are you on Firefox no no
no no I'm on
Chrome Joel so weird you've got some
filter on for sure or something like
that you think I'll open it in incognit
yeah just just try that um but the Ping
attribute I thought was really
interesting because I I didn't know that
you could trigger that post request
specifically with an a tag um and I
think this could be helpful for one
leaking location hre via these um these
ping from ping to headers and then um
for two I think this could be applicable
in sort of like a client side path
traversal slash uh
um text injection or HTML injection to C
surf environment right where you can
sort of create this a tag dynamically
and when the user clicks on it you
trigger some C- surf that happens on the
website and I think this would also be
really helpful in an environment where
um there are same site strict cookies
where the request must originate from
the the same origin for the cookies to
be sent um so if you can get an a tag
injection and add the Ping attribute
then you can trigger that that post
request Joel do you still knock that
have it man I I'm going to send you a
video oh my God Jo all right well all
right let do dude let's let's end it
here let's call it a wrap and uh and
I'll go troubleshoot your instance all
right let's go okay all right dude this
is a good episode and that's a wrap on
this episode of critical thinking thanks
so much for listening and if you want
more critical thinking content head over
to ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack along
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there